

Vamsi Batchu

UX Designer & Frontend Dev

UX/UI Designer and Front-end developer with a passion for designing clean and functional user experiences. I enjoy turning complex problems into beautiful and intuitive interface designs. Also, a full-time landloper, travel Jedi and a soccer fanatic.



vbatchu1@student.gsu.edu

(404) 906 - 2645

User Experience User Research **Content Audit** Heuristic Evaluation Metrics Analysis **Quantitative Survey ZMET** Ideation **User Stories** Personas Scenarios Story Boards **Empathy Maps Mood Boards** Site Maps Mental Models **Process Diagrams** Task Grids **User Journeys**

Web Development

Visual Design

Usability testing

HTML, CSS, JavaScript LESS, Sass, jQuery Angular JS Backbone.js Bootstrap AJAX, CRUD REST, PHP, MongoDB, Node.js

Information Architecture, Wireframing and Mock ups



Career Summary

User Experience (UX) Designer with 3 years of experience designing engaging and user-friendly interfaces for native and web applications for both desktop and mobile. I have immense passion to transform complex problems into simple and elegant solutions.

- O Experienced in designing & developing iOS and Android Applications, conducting User Research activities, including heuristic reviews, usability testing, competitive product analysis, gathering web metrics data, field research, quantitative surveys, user interviews, lead User discovery & Stakeholder workshops.
- O Proficient in UCD methodologies & Lean UX strategies such as Personas, User flows, Wireframes, Interactive Prototypes, Heuristic evaluations, A/B and Usability Testing. Skilled with a variety of Rapid Prototyping and visualization tools (Axure, Omnigraffle, Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, InVision, Marvel etc.)
- O Front end developer with experience on HTML/UI, JS frameworks (Node, React), rich user interface design, development, standards, media (screen, mobile, touch interface) compatibilities, application architecture and visual design.



Education

Georgia State University

Masters Degree - Computer Science Aug 2017 - Present GPA - 3.83

SRM University

Bachelors Degree - Computer Science Aug 2011 - May 2015 GPA - 4.00



Skill Stack





















Framer.js

Principle App

Balsamiq

Sketch

Work Experience

Georgia State University Graduate UX Researcher

Aug 2017 - Present

Member of Creative Media Industries Institute (CMII). Worked on design architecture of multiple web and mobile applications of the university. Also worked on designing and Implementing an "Interactive Gamification model of the Course Curriculum" which would be used by all the new students enrolling each semester.

Proofread, edited and reformatted research papers. Performed design, collection and analysis of evaluative project data and was responsible for tool development. Participated in the development of a framework, with methods and tools to support visualization of sports related data through the decades.

Worked on designing the mobile architecure & built an Artificial Intelligent App/Chatbot which will have conversations with people, ask questions, track mental health 24/7 and help them get over stress, depression through various computerized cognitive behavioral therapies (CBTs).

Unisys Corporation UX Designer

May 2015 - Aug 2017

Designed high-impact, user-centered Web sites with a strong emotional appeal, sophisticated production values and intuitive navigation to maximize user engagement and cement powerful brand identities.

Partnered with user interface designers, Web developers and UX managers to translate information architecture, navigation and process flows into beautiful and easy-to-use solutions.

Established UX design as the first stage of all Web and mobile application development, instituting a user-centered design (UCD) approach. Gathered user data through methods such as analytics reporting, task analysis, and participatory design techniques and utilized that data to drive design decisions.

Gathered requirements from clients and conducted a focus group to discover user needs. Developed user personas and scenarios in order to enhance functionality and usability for key audiences. Organized, tailored, and moderated local and virtual user testing sessions based on personas , use cases. Designed mock-ups for potential and existing clients to show how our applications would look if integrated into their systems.

Produced style guides and web/CSS/interaction specification sheets for engineers. Designed and generated fully-interactive HTML prototypes and click-throughs which were used for client presentations, mock-ups, as well as usertesting studies.

Highlights

Worked on more than 18 projects based on Web , Mobile and IoT

Led a team of 6 Junior UX researchers to perform end to end design architecture for a Public Sector Child Welfare Information system called SACWIS (Michigan State)

Created a Design Framework called 'Interfaces' which consists of structured processes to develop Human centered Systems. This framework has been a differentiator and played a critical role in winning 14 RFPs for the company.

Created a repository of Reusable Design Elements (1000+) and interactions with HTML/JS codes, prototypes which reduced the development time by 40%.

Achieved a Customer Satisfaction Rating of 9+ on 10 for all the projects handled.

Unisys Corporation UX Design Intern

Jan 2015 - May 2015

Participated in user-centered design sessions with the UX Lead and UX Designer to scope design goals and criteria.

Assisted in the creation of sketches and wireframes for user interface (UI) designs.

Assisted in the creation of storyboards to explain a workflow or scenario to stakeholders.

Designed and developed prototype designs under the direction of the UX Lead.

Created and maintained clear documentation on design revisions and feedback from design reviews. Developed workflows using a prototype tool and tested scenarios and UI/UX issues.

Highlights

Redesigned and developed a Responsive Web application called Transport Management System using UCD methodologies & developed using Bootstrap/SASS and JS technologies which improved the user base by 25%

Interviewed partners and users using the **ZMET technique** to discover deeper subconscious level of thoughts and insights useful for design process.

Achieved 'Valued Contributor' award during the Internship Program.